<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- name="GENERATOR" content="github.com/mmarkdown/mmark markdown processor for Go" -->
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM 'rfc2629.dtd' []>
<rfc ipr="trust200902" submissionType="independent" category="exp" xml:lang="en" consensus="no" docName="draft-judsys1-00">
<?rfc toc="yes"?><?rfc symrefs="yes"?><?rfc sortrefs="yes"?><?rfc compact="yes"?><?rfc subcompact="no"?><?rfc comments="no"?>
<front>
<title abbrev="JUDSYS1">JSON Unified Digital Signatures System Standard 1</title><author initials="G." surname="Queiroz" fullname="Gabriel Villela Noriega de Queiroz"><organization></organization><address><postal><street></street>
<city></city>
<code></code>
<country></country>
<region></region>
</postal><phone></phone>
<email>gabrieljvnq@gmail.com</email>
<uri></uri>
</address></author>
<date year="2018" month="8" day="27"></date>
<area>Internet</area><workgroup></workgroup><keyword>cryptography</keyword>
<keyword>digital signature</keyword>
<keyword>protocol</keyword>

<abstract>
<t>A simple digital signature standard designed to be used by regular people and to be of mandatory acceptance.</t>
</abstract>

</front>

<middle>

<section anchor="introduction" title="Introduction">
<t>Currently, ITI, the government body responsible of ICP-Brasil, Brazil's PKI (Public Key Infrastructure), endorses three different standards: CAdES, XAdES and PAdES.</t>
<t>Since they are all based on X.509 which is used in SSL, there should be an abundance of good software libraries and end user applications to support at least one of these standard.</t>
<t>This is not the case. While there have been some efforts to write open source libraries and end user applications for ICP-Brasil, they are hard to find and most seem unfinished and abandoned.</t>
<t>ITI provides a digital signature verification web tool, but it is only for CAdES and doesn't seem to work well.</t>
<t>PAdES is a monster of its own kind. In an attempt to replicate the paper experience in the digital world, a PDF file can be signed, edited and resigned by another person in a way that they signed over different version of the same document. This is both hard to implement and hard to explain to end users.</t>
<t>To make matters worse, PDF readers almost never come with the necessary CAs to verify ICP-Brasil digital signatures.</t>
<t>Perhaps as result of this mess of different standards, the ITI admits that, no one is obliged to accept digital signatures in Brazil:</t>
<t>
<list style="empty">
<t>In face of the authenticity generated by the usage of ICP-Brasil digital certificates, is it correct to assert that everyone (government bodies, banks, private citizens, etc.) must accept them?<vspace />
.<vspace />
The answer is negative. As noted, ICP-Brasil confers legal validity to electronic manifestations. However, no entity nor government body nor private agent is required by law to accept digitally signed electronic documents.<vspace />
.<vspace />
And this is for a simple reason: even though we live in an information society, many entities, both public and private, do not yet find themselves adherent to this new technological paradigm. They may even simply lack the necessary equipments to receive, verify and store digitally signed documents.</t>
<t><eref target="http://www.iti.gov.br/perguntas-frequentes/41-perguntas-frequentes/567-questoes-juridicas#r21">http://www.iti.gov.br/perguntas-frequentes/41-perguntas-frequentes/567-questoes-juridicas#r21</eref> (in Portuguese), ITI - Instituto Nacional de Tecnologia da Informação
</t>
</list></t>
<t>This situation is unacceptable. We need a digital signature standard that:</t>
<t>
<list style="numbers">
<t>Is easy for programmers to implement. Including reference libraries in multiple languages.</t>
<t>Is easy for ordinary people to use on a day to day basis.</t>
<t>Has strict rules to avoid interoperability problems.</t>
<t>Has mandatory acceptance by law.</t>
</list>
</t>
<t>This document aims to provide a digital signature standard that address points one through three. Hopefully, this standard may fulfil the fourth point in the near future.</t>

<section anchor="terminology" title="Terminology">
<t>The keywords MUST, MUST NOT, REQUIRED, SHALL, SHALL NOT, SHOULD,
SHOULD NOT, RECOMMENDED, MAY, and OPTIONAL, when they appear in this
document, are to be interpreted as described in <xref target="RFC2119"></xref>.</t>
<t>All apps MUST use the standard translations present in this document when they present in the Language specific rules section.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">User</spanx>: A human being using a JUDSYS app. Unless otherwise specified, users MUST ALWAYS be considered as non-tech-savvy people.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">Signing app</spanx>: A computer program that digitally signs documents according to this standard.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">Verifier app</spanx>: A computer program that verifies a digital signature according to this standard.</t>
<t>(<spanx style="strong">App</spanx>) <spanx style="strong">JUDSYS app</spanx>: A computer program that is either a singing app or a verifier app or both.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">Subject qualifiers</spanx>: Certain values that qualify the subject. Ex: email, full name, government issued identification numbers, et cetera.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">Natrual person</spanx>: A human beign.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">Legal person</spanx>: A group of people who the Law considers to be its own person.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">Digital signature</spanx>:</t>
<t>(<spanx style="strong">PKI</spanx>) <spanx style="strong">Public Key Infrastructure</spanx>:</t>
<t>(<spanx style="strong">KP</spanx>) <spanx style="strong">Key Pair</spanx>:</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">Certificate</spanx>: A short signed message that states a key pair is in the control of a specific subject.</t>
<t>(<spanx style="strong">CA</spanx>) <spanx style="strong">Certificate Authority</spanx>: A certificate that is allowed to sign other certificates. This is, a CA is an entity (usually a company or government body) that ensures that the subject on a certificate is really the person it names.</t>
<t>(<spanx style="strong">PA</spanx>) <spanx style="strong">Proof of attribute</spanx>: A short signed message in which the issuer certifies that a certain attribute is true. Examples: job titles and permissions delegated by the issuer to the subject.</t>
<t>(<spanx style="strong">TA</spanx>) <spanx style="strong">Timestamping Authority</spanx></t>
<t>This is very similar to the concept of attribute certificates. The names was changed to avoid using the &quot;certificate&quot; in two different contexts that may confuse users.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">ICAO</spanx>: <spanx style="emph">International Civil Aviation Organization</spanx>.</t>
<t><spanx style="strong">JSON</spanx>: <spanx style="emph">Javascript Object Notation</spanx>.</t>
</section>
</section>

<section anchor="security-considerations" title="Security Considerations">
<t>Correct functioning of security mechanisms depend critically on the
evil bit being set properly.  If faulty components do not set the
evil bit to 1 when appropriate, firewalls will not be able to do
their jobs properly.  Similarly, if the bit is set to 1 when it
shouldn't be, a denial of service condition may occur.</t>
</section>

</middle>

<back>
<references title="Normative References">
<?rfc include="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml"?>
</references>

</back>

</rfc>
